{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Entrepreneur",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "Week-2",
    "LastModified": "14 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Week-2"
    ]
  },
 "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What allows the entrepreneur to see things in a very positive and optimistic way in the midst of difficult situation?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurial mind frame",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneurial heart flame",
        "Entrepreneurial gut game",
        "Passion",
        "Entrepreneurial mind frame"
      ],
      "reference": "Essentials in Entrepreneur's Opportunity Seeking",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the entrepreneur's driven passion, where they are attracted to discover satisfaction in the act and process of discovery?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurial heart flame",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneurial mind frame",
        "Entrepreneurial gut game",
        "Passion",
        "Entrepreneurial heart flame"
      ],
      "reference": "Essentials in Entrepreneur's Opportunity Seeking",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the great desire of an entrepreneur to achieve his/her goals?",
      "answer": "Passion",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneurial mind frame",
        "Entrepreneurial heart flame",
        "Entrepreneurial gut game",
        "Passion"
      ],
      "reference": "Essentials in Entrepreneur's Opportunity Seeking",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the ability of the entrepreneur of being intuitive?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurial gut game",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneurial mind frame",
        "Entrepreneurial heart flame",
        "Entrepreneurial Intuition",
        "Entrepreneurial gut game"
      ],
      "reference": "Essentials in Entrepreneur's Opportunity Seeking",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another term for the ability of the entrepreneur of being intuitive?",
      "answer": "Intuition",
      "choices": [
        "Entrepreneurial mind frame",
        "Entrepreneurial heart flame",
        "Entrepreneurial gut game",
        "Intuition"
      ],
      "reference": "Essentials in Entrepreneur's Opportunity Seeking",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes the weather conditions?",
      "answer": "Climate",
      "choices": [
        "Natural resources",
        "Wildlife",
        "Physical environment",
        "Climate"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes minerals, forests, water, and fertile land that occur in nature and can be used for economic gain?",
      "answer": "Natural resources",
      "choices": [
        "Climate",
        "Wildlife",
        "Physical environment",
        "Natural resources"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes all mammals, birds, reptiles, fish, etc., that live in the wild?",
      "answer": "Wildlife",
      "choices": [
        "Climate",
        "Natural resources",
        "Physical environment",
        "Wildlife"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes all the laws, rules, and regulations that govern business practices as well as the permits, approvals, and licenses necessary to operate the business?",
      "answer": "Political forces",
      "choices": [
        "Economic forces",
        "Sociocultural forces",
        "Technological environment",
        "Political forces"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes forces such as income level and employment rate?",
      "answer": "Economic forces",
      "choices": [
        "Political forces",
        "Sociocultural forces",
        "Technological environment",
        "Economic forces"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes customs, lifestyles and values that characterize a society?",
      "answer": "Sociocultural forces",
      "choices": [
        "Political forces",
        "Economic forces",
        "Technological environment",
        "Sociocultural forces"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What includes new inventions and technology innovations?",
      "answer": "Technological environment",
      "choices": [
        "Political forces",
        "Economic forces",
        "Sociocultural forces",
        "Technological environment"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What arises when changes happen in the external environment?",
      "answer": "Entrepreneurial ideas",
      "choices": [
        "Technological discovery",
        "People's interest",
        "Past experiences",
        "Entrepreneurial ideas"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the physical environment, societal environment, and industry environment where the business operates?",
      "answer": "External environment",
      "choices": [
        "Internal environment",
        "Competitive environment",
        "Market environment",
        "External environment"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What sees the possibility of business opportunities in any new discovery or because of the use of latest technology?",
      "answer": "A person with entrepreneurial interest",
      "choices": [
        "A government official",
        "A regular consumer",
        "A past employee",
        "A person with entrepreneurial interest"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are also good sources of ideas from the government?",
      "answer": "Priorities, projects, programs, and policies",
      "choices": [
        "Technological discoveries",
        "People's interests",
        "Past experiences",
        "Priorities, projects, programs, and policies"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are a rich source of entrepreneurial ideas related to people?",
      "answer": "The interest, hobbies, and preferences of people",
      "choices": [
        "Government policies",
        "Technological advancements",
        "Past experiences",
        "The interest, hobbies, and preferences of people"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What may lead to the opening of related business enterprise based on a person's history?",
      "answer": "The expertise and skills developed by a person",
      "choices": [
        "Government programs",
        "People's interests",
        "Technological discoveries",
        "The expertise and skills developed by a person"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What source of opportunity comes from the expertise and skills developed by a person who has worked in a particular field?",
      "answer": "Past experiences",
      "choices": [
        "Technological discovery and advancement",
        "Government’s thrust, programs, and policies",
        "People’s interest",
        "Past experiences"
      ],
      "reference": "Sources of Opportunities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the act or process of trying to get or win something?",
      "answer": "Competition",
      "choices": [
        "Rivalry",
        "Substitute",
        "Bargaining",
        "Competition"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are the ones that pay cash in exchange to your goods and services?",
      "answer": "Buyers",
      "choices": [
        "Suppliers",
        "Competitors",
        "New entrants",
        "Buyers"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is defined as the one who enters something?",
      "answer": "A new entrant",
      "choices": [
        "A buyer",
        "A supplier",
        "A competitor",
        "A new entrant"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a state or situation in which people or groups are competing with each other?",
      "answer": "Rivalry",
      "choices": [
        "Competition",
        "Substitution",
        "Supply",
        "Rivalry"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is anything that takes the place or function of another?",
      "answer": "Substitute",
      "choices": [
        "Rivalry",
        "Competition",
        "Supply",
        "Substitute"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are the ones that provide something that is needed or wanted?",
      "answer": "Suppliers",
      "choices": [
        "Buyers",
        "Competitors",
        "New entrants",
        "Suppliers"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another name for the Forces of Competition Model?",
      "answer": "Five forces of competition",
      "choices": [
        "Sources of Opportunities",
        "Entrepreneurial Process",
        "Essentials in Seeking",
        "Five forces of competition"
      ],
      "reference": "Forces of Competition Model",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    }
  ]
}